John R. Brandon, PhD

jbrandon@gmail.com (206) 919–6541 Pacifica,CA LinkedIn Profile
Open Source Code on GitHub

John provides modeling and statistical support to his clients, including a National Science Foundation initiative for Fishery Science, and The Makah Tribal Council (Neah Bay, WA). Previously he worked as a staff environmental consultant, developing photo-identification, and point- and line-transect survey designs for ecological monitoring studies in Alaska and Canada.

	_ Education
2003-2009	PhD, School of Aquatic and Fisheries Sciences, University of Washington (UW).
1994-1998	BSc, Ecology, Behavior and Evolution, University of California, San Diego (UCSD).
	Additional Coursework
2015	High Performance Scientific Computing, Applied-Math-583, UW (Audited).
2001	Computer Intensive Statistical Techniques, SIO-279, Scripps Institute of Oceanography.
2000	UCSD Computer Science Extension: Visual Basic II: Intermediate, CSE-40159. Visual Basic III: Object Oriented Programming, CSE-40328.
	Professional Positions
2016—present	Population Dynamics and Statistical Consultant to the The Makah Tribal Council.
2014-present	Management Strategy Consultant to a U.S. National Science Foundation's initiative for Fishery Science.
2009–2015	Biostatistician / Fisheries Scientist (Staff at LGL and Greeneridge Sciences, Inc.).

Applied Statistical Experience

- Simulation modeling of dynamic feedback systems
- Bayesian inference
- Regression / Generalized linear models
- Mixed-effects (hierarchical) models

Recent Computing Experience

- R %>% R Markdown
- Fortran 90/95 (GNU GCC)
- Git / GitHub
- AD Model Builder (C++ language expression for auto-differentiation)